<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Welcome to Prafull's blog</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Welcome to Prafull's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 18:21:01 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://prafullchvn.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Problems while setting Up React Native developer environment</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/setting-up-react-native-env/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 18:21:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/setting-up-react-native-env/</guid><description>Build failed. Failed to execute the installDebug command in android. This problem happens mainly when your virtual device is running less on memory and is trying to install new build but failing because of insufficient storage.
To solve this -
Uninstall the previous build and try running build again. Wipe the data of virtual device You can do this by going to virtual device manager. Then Click vertical ellipsis symbol. Click on option to wipe data.</description></item><item><title>How to Know Worth of Something</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/how-to-know-worth-of-something/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 17:00:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/how-to-know-worth-of-something/</guid><description>Why something is there? Thinking about why something exist, what is need of that thing gives great insights into why something is needed.
What would happen if somethign is there? This question tells about importance of that thing. What role does it play. Human nature is like it doesn&amp;rsquo;t know value of something until it is not there.</description></item><item><title>Interfaces in Java</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/interfaces-in-java/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 12:39:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/interfaces-in-java/</guid><description>In java, whenever you pass some value to some function, the type of value that you pass to that function defines the contract. As long as your the values satisfies the contract you are good to go.
Interface is good example of it. Interaface can be created to enforce some contract.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take example of payment using some payment instrument like credit card, debit card or net banking.
What contract these all should satisfy so that amount can withdrawn from these.</description></item><item><title>Interfaces in Java</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/interfaces/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 12:39:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/interfaces/</guid><description>In java, whenever you pass some value to some function, the type of value that you pass to that function defines the contract. As long as your the values satisfies the contract you are good to go.
Interface is good example of it. Interaface can be created to enforce some contract.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take example of payment using some payment instrument like credit card, debit card or net banking.
What contract these all should satisfy so that amount can withdrawn from these.</description></item><item><title>Testing Java Code Using Junit</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/testing-java-code-using-junit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 11:37:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/testing-java-code-using-junit/</guid><description>Conecpts Container
A node in test tree that contains other tests or container
Test
A method in test tree that checks the assertion.
Life Cycle methods
Methods which are executed at particular moment of execution of tree node. Generall they are marked using @BeforeEach, @AfterEach, @BeforeAll and @AfterAll.
Test Class
Any top-level class, static member class or nested class that contains at least one method i.e. container. Test classes must not be abstract and must have a single constructor.</description></item><item><title>Separating Src and Class Files in Java</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/separating-src-and-class-files-in-java/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 15:54:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/separating-src-and-class-files-in-java/</guid><description>src directory It is directory where all the .java file are stored. Generally in structure which your package should follow.
out directory It is directory where all the .class file are stored. It also follows structure of package.
Example
├── out │ └── com │ └── tw │ └── step │ └── graphics │ ├── Canvas.class │ ├── ShapesMain.class │ └── shapes │ ├── Circle.class │ └── Rectangle.class ├── shapes.jar └── src └── com └── tw └── step └── graphics ├── Canvas.</description></item><item><title>Jar Files in Java</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/jar-files-in-java/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 15:18:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/jar-files-in-java/</guid><description>JAR file (Java Archive) JAR file is used to bundle the software files. This makes it easier to send across the devices and run it without hussle.
Syntax jar {ctxui}[vfmn0PMe] [jar-file] [manifest-file] [entry-point] [-C dir] files ... Options c : Create jar file. t : Print content of jar file. C : Change to specified directory. e : To indicate that entry point is mensioned in command. x : To extract the files from jar file.</description></item><item><title>Packages in Java</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/packages-in-java/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 11:27:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/packages-in-java/</guid><description>Package Package is group of related types.
Types here mean
classes interfaces E.g. java.lang is package with basec classes of java, java.io is package with reading and writing classes
Creating package First, you have to decide on package name. You have to mension package name in each file which is to be included in that package.
package com.example.className; It must be first line of file. Each file can belong to only one package which means we can&amp;rsquo;t write above line more than once in file.</description></item><item><title>Debugging in Chrome</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/debugging-in-chrome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 18:38:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/debugging-in-chrome/</guid><description>How to debug in chrome? Most obvious answer will be console.log. But writing console.log all over the places can get messy.
But there are some easy ways to do that.
Live Expression Open DevTools &amp;gt; Go to console tab &amp;gt; click on eye like symbol
Type expressin that you wanna watch. This expression will be maintained for all the site you visit. Instead of flooding your console it will show the live value.</description></item><item><title>Isolation Property</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/isolation-property/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 17:48:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/isolation-property/</guid><description>z-index Z index is used to push the element to behind some other element on HTML page.
Syntax :
z-index: &amp;lt;number&amp;gt;; But z-index by default pushed it to the back of element with respect to whole document.
But sometime this is not case. We want to push the element to back in particular group of elements and not with respect to document elements.
So in that case you can use isolation property on parent element to isolate it from other element in document and then you can put z-index on it.</description></item><item><title>First Post</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/first-post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 17:21:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/first-post/</guid><description>My favorite quote It is always impossible until it is done. - Nelson Mandela</description></item></channel></rss>