<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Welcome to Prafull's blog</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Welcome to Prafull's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 08:45:49 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://prafullchvn.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Desired State and Current State</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/infra/desired-state-and-current-state/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 08:45:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/infra/desired-state-and-current-state/</guid><description>Desired state One of the primary funciton of Terraform is to create real world resource that is described in Terraform Configuration file.
Current state This is state of currently running resource.
Terraform tries to match the desired state mensioned in TF configuration file. So if any property that is mensioned in TF state file is manually changed, TF will try to change it to match the desired state. Note: If some property that is not mensioned in TF configuration is changed then TF won&amp;rsquo;t try to change it because it is not configured in configuratio file.</description></item><item><title>Terraform State File</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/infra/tf-state-file/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 08:32:10 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/infra/tf-state-file/</guid><description>Terraform stores the state of real world resource created in file called terraform state file. Whenever trying to create the resource it terraform fetches cross checks it against state file. Before doing that it fetches the states from real world i.e. it refreshes the state. It contains the information about all the live resources. It contains all the informtion about the live running resource.</description></item><item><title>Authenticate With Gitlab in Tf</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/infra/authenticate-with-gitlab-in-tf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 08:23:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/infra/authenticate-with-gitlab-in-tf/</guid><description>How to authenticate with gitlab for fetching module To authenticate with GitLab in Terraform and fetch a module from a GitLab repository, you can use a personal access token. Here are the general steps:
Generate a personal access token: In GitLab, go to your user settings and generate a personal access token with the &amp;ldquo;api&amp;rdquo; scope. Take note of the token value, as you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to see it again.</description></item><item><title>Provider in Tf</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/infra/provider-in-tf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 08:19:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/infra/provider-in-tf/</guid><description>TF Provider Plugins to interact with various cloud vendors. Available in TF registry Provider configuration It is generally stored in root directory of module.
These configuration are global to all files.
provider &amp;#34;name-of-provider&amp;#34; { # config required by provider lias = &amp;#34;some-alias&amp;#34; vaersion = &amp;#34;~&amp;gt;3.0&amp;#34; } These provider need to be declared in required_provider block of terraform block.
terraform { required_providers { mycloud = { source = &amp;#34;mycorp/mycloud&amp;#34; version = &amp;#34;~&amp;gt;1.</description></item><item><title>Nodeport Service in K8</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/infra/nodeport-service-in-k8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 15:51:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/infra/nodeport-service-in-k8/</guid><description>Here to demonstrate the use of nodeport service we will create some nginx pod and nodeport service to access it.
Deployment file apiVersion: apps/v1 kind: Deployment metadata: name: nginx-deployment labels: app: nginx spec: replicas: 3 selector: matchLabels: app: testing template: metadata: labels: app: testing for: nodeport-svc spec: containers: - name: nginx image: nginx:1.14.2 ports: - containerPort: 80 Here we are creating 3 pods with nginx running inside of it. We have exposed port 80 of container.</description></item><item><title>Yaml in Kubernetes</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/infra/yaml-in-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 15:43:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/infra/yaml-in-kubernetes/</guid><description>Fields in kubernetes Example :
apiVersion: v1 kind: Pod metadata: name: pod-demo labels: pod-name: yaml-in-k8-tutorial spec: containers: - name: nginx-container image: nginx apiVersion - String Depending on what type of resource you are trying to create apiVersion will change.
Syntax Description POD v1 Service v1 Replica Set app/v1 Deployment app/v1 How to choose apiVersion if there are two options available:
Latest Compatiblity Depedency kind - String It is type of resource that we are trying to create.</description></item><item><title>Codepush Setup for Android</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/codepush/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 10:50:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/codepush/</guid><description>Codepush is feature that allows to make changes in code on live application.
Codepush is microsoft solution to update code. Only JS code (in case of React Native). Fastest way to apply quick changes Codepush supports React Native. In Case of react native, using codepush we can make changes in JS code only. Setting up Codepush
In order to implement there are 4 broader steps.
Create app on app center. Implement SDK in project.</description></item><item><title>Destraction Quote</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/destraction-quote/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 16:38:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/destraction-quote/</guid><description>Distaction at its core is just confusion about what matters.</description></item><item><title>Refactoring variable or keyword in Vscode</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/refactoring-var-name-in-vscode/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 12:38:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/refactoring-var-name-in-vscode/</guid><description>To refactor the variable name in particular file in vscode.
Take cursor to the variable name and press f2 to change name. To see the priview where all the change will be applied press shift + f2.
Refactoring something which is not the variable name
Press command + shift + f2 Expanding the drop down you will get an option to replace. If you wanna skip some file, then you can hover over file and press cross in front of that file to skip that file from being changed.</description></item><item><title>Testing in React Native Project</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/testing-in-react-native-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 08:33:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/testing-in-react-native-project/</guid><description>Setup npm install --save-dev @testing-library/react-native --legacy-peer-deps Jest function Syntax -
expecte(actual).______; // where _____ you can put building method to assert further Jest Api functions General functions expect(value).toEqual(someOtherValue); expect(value).toStrictEqual(someOtherValue); expect(value).toMatch(/someRegex/); expect(someObject).toMatchObject(subsetOfObject); expect(value).toBeTruth(); expect(value).toBeFalsy(); expect(value).toBeDefined(); expect(value).toBeUndefined(); expect(value).toBeNull(); expect(value).toBeNaN(); Based on assertion made expect.assertions(3); // ensures that 3 assertion have been made in test expect.hasAssertions(); // ensures that test have at least one assertion Asserting the array You can check whether array have particular value or not.</description></item><item><title>Altriusm Quote by Dalai Lama</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/altriusm-quote-by-dalai-lama/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 09:32:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/altriusm-quote-by-dalai-lama/</guid><description>“Idealistic as it may sound, altruism should be the driving force in business, not just competition and a desire for wealth.”
&amp;ndash; Dalai Lama</description></item><item><title>Mistakes Done While Using Usestate Hook</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/mistakes-done-while-using-usestate-hook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 16:56:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/mistakes-done-while-using-usestate-hook/</guid><description>Mistakes while using non primitve state Same reference problem When state is of non primitive type then comparison is done based on reference. So even if value is changed but reference is same then it won&amp;rsquo;t execute the render the component again. To avoid this create copy of the state the pass it to setter of state.
To avoid this
In case of object, you can create copy by using spread operator for unchanged part of state and then putting changed part to be merged with it.</description></item><item><title>Useeffect Hook in React</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/useeffect-hook-in-react/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 16:31:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/useeffect-hook-in-react/</guid><description>useEffect hook in react native is one of the very useful and most used hook, (at least for me it is ;) ). There are various versions of useEffect hook that I am going to talk about in this blog.
Without dependency Following version of useEffect runs the callback each time the component that it is used in is rendered.
Syntax -
useEffect(() =&amp;gt; { /** * some code here */ }); With dependency Following version of useEffect is executed each time depedency is changes.</description></item><item><title>Problems while setting Up React Native developer environment</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/setting-up-react-native-env/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 18:21:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/setting-up-react-native-env/</guid><description>Build failed. Failed to execute the installDebug command in android. This problem happens mainly when your virtual device is running less on memory and is trying to install new build but failing because of insufficient storage.
To solve this -
Uninstall the previous build and try running build again. Wipe the data of virtual device You can do this by going to virtual device manager. Then Click vertical ellipsis symbol. Click on option to wipe data.</description></item><item><title>How to Know Worth of Something</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/how-to-know-worth-of-something/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 17:00:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/how-to-know-worth-of-something/</guid><description>Why something is there? Thinking about why something exist, what is need of that thing gives great insights into why something is needed.
What would happen if somethign is there? This question tells about importance of that thing. What role does it play. Human nature is like it doesn&amp;rsquo;t know value of something until it is not there.</description></item><item><title>Interfaces in Java</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/interfaces-in-java/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 12:39:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/interfaces-in-java/</guid><description>In java, whenever you pass some value to some function, the type of value that you pass to that function defines the contract. As long as your the values satisfies the contract you are good to go.
Interface is good example of it. Interaface can be created to enforce some contract.
Let&amp;rsquo;s take example of payment using some payment instrument like credit card, debit card or net banking.
What contract these all should satisfy so that amount can withdrawn from these.</description></item><item><title>Testing Java Code Using Junit</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/testing-java-code-using-junit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 11:37:32 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/testing-java-code-using-junit/</guid><description>Conecpts Container
A node in test tree that contains other tests or container
Test
A method in test tree that checks the assertion.
Life Cycle methods
Methods which are executed at particular moment of execution of tree node. Generall they are marked using @BeforeEach, @AfterEach, @BeforeAll and @AfterAll.
Test Class
Any top-level class, static member class or nested class that contains at least one method i.e. container. Test classes must not be abstract and must have a single constructor.</description></item><item><title>Separating Src and Class Files in Java</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/separating-src-and-class-files-in-java/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 15:54:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/separating-src-and-class-files-in-java/</guid><description>src directory It is directory where all the .java file are stored. Generally in structure which your package should follow.
out directory It is directory where all the .class file are stored. It also follows structure of package.
Example
├── out │ └── com │ └── tw │ └── step │ └── graphics │ ├── Canvas.class │ ├── ShapesMain.class │ └── shapes │ ├── Circle.class │ └── Rectangle.class ├── shapes.jar └── src └── com └── tw └── step └── graphics ├── Canvas.</description></item><item><title>Jar Files in Java</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/jar-files-in-java/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 15:18:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/jar-files-in-java/</guid><description>JAR file (Java Archive) JAR file is used to bundle the software files. This makes it easier to send across the devices and run it without hussle.
Syntax jar {ctxui}[vfmn0PMe] [jar-file] [manifest-file] [entry-point] [-C dir] files ... Options c : Create jar file. t : Print content of jar file. C : Change to specified directory. e : To indicate that entry point is mensioned in command. x : To extract the files from jar file.</description></item><item><title>Packages in Java</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/packages-in-java/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 11:27:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/packages-in-java/</guid><description>Package Package is group of related types.
Types here mean
classes interfaces E.g. java.lang is package with basec classes of java, java.io is package with reading and writing classes
Creating package First, you have to decide on package name. You have to mension package name in each file which is to be included in that package.
package com.example.className; It must be first line of file. Each file can belong to only one package which means we can&amp;rsquo;t write above line more than once in file.</description></item><item><title>Debugging in Chrome</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/debugging-in-chrome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 18:38:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/debugging-in-chrome/</guid><description>How to debug in chrome? Most obvious answer will be console.log. But writing console.log all over the places can get messy.
But there are some easy ways to do that.
Live Expression Open DevTools &amp;gt; Go to console tab &amp;gt; click on eye like symbol
Type expressin that you wanna watch. This expression will be maintained for all the site you visit. Instead of flooding your console it will show the live value.</description></item><item><title>Isolation Property</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/isolation-property/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 17:48:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/isolation-property/</guid><description>z-index Z index is used to push the element to behind some other element on HTML page.
Syntax :
z-index: &amp;lt;number&amp;gt;; But z-index by default pushed it to the back of element with respect to whole document.
But sometime this is not case. We want to push the element to back in particular group of elements and not with respect to document elements.
So in that case you can use isolation property on parent element to isolate it from other element in document and then you can put z-index on it.</description></item><item><title>First Post</title><link>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/first-post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 17:21:38 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://prafullchvn.github.io/posts/first-post/</guid><description>My favorite quote It is always impossible until it is done. - Nelson Mandela</description></item></channel></rss>